Bendix, Reinhard; Papers ger021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence Files, 1948-1987; 2; 163 file folders
  - Correspondence concerning the 1978 meeting of the International Sociological Association, 2.97 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1-9)
    - Cardoso, Fernando Enrique, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
    - Chirot, Daniel, 1976-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
    - Dahrendorf, Ralf, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
    - Eckstein, Susan, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
    - Evers, Hans-Dieter, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
    - Friedrichs, Robert W., 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
    - Goldfrank, Walter L., 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
    - Hermassi, Elbaki, 1977-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
    - Higley, John, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
    - Lötsch, Manfred, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
    - Matejko, Alexander, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Riabushkin, T. V., 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Richard, Michel P., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Sharma, Kailas N., 1977-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
    - Stavenhagen, Rudolfo, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Szmatka, Jacek, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Tominaga, Ken'ichi, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Watanuki, Joji, 1976-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
    - Weiss, Jane Alison, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
  - Irschick, Gene, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
  - Jackson, Robert, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
  - Jacobsen, Kenneth, 1978-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
  - Janowitz, Morris, 1966; 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
  - Johnson, Bruce, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
  - Johnson, Chalmers, 1976-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
  - Jowitt, Kenneth, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
  - K - L -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
  - Kabongo, Ilunga, 1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
  - Kalberg, Stephen, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
  - Kang, Jung In, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
  - Kantowsky, Detlef, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
  - Kautsky, John H., 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
  - Knight, Walter, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
  - König, René, 1979-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
  - Kohli, Atul, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19)
  - Kothari, Rajni, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
  - Kühnhardt, Ludger, 1986; reprint (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 21)
  - Kunz, Andreas, 1976-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 22)
  - Kwok, Siu-tong, 1979-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
  - Lacklen, John, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
  - Laslett, Barbara (Social Science History Association), 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
  - Laufer, Heinz, 1981-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 24)
  - Laumann, Edward O., 1981-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul F., 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
  - Lee, Alfred McClung, 1951; 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
  - Lee, Dorothy, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
  - Leo Baeck Institute, 1980-1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 27)
  - Lepsius, M. Rainer, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
  - Levenberg, Nancy Elizabeth, 1976-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
  - Leventman, Paula, 1976-1977; reprint (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 29)
  - Levine, Barry B., 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
  - Levine, Donald N., 1986; reprint (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
  - Lipset, Seymour Martin (Marty), 1951-1952; 1977-1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 31)
  - Lösche, Peter, 1988 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
  - Long, Norton E., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
  - Luke, Timothy, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 33)
  - Lynd, Helen M., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 34)
  - Lynd, Robert, 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 34)
  - M - O -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 35)
  - Marsh, Donald C., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 36)
  - Mavrogordatos, George Th, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 36)
  - May, Henry F., 1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
  - Mayntz, Renate, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 37)
  - McNutt, Helma, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
  - Meeks, Wayne, 1984-1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 38)
  - Merriam, Charles, 1948 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Merton, Robert K., 1952; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 39)
  - Meuschel, Sigrid, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 40)
  - Meyer, Richard A., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
  - Miller, Abraham H., 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
  - Morawska, Ewa, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 41)
  - Mueller, Hans-Eberhard, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
  - Muir, William K. (Sandy), 1980-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 42)
  - National Humanities Center, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - National Public Radio, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 43)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
  - Nisbet, Robert, 1965; 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 44)
  - Norbu, Dawa, 1982-1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 45)
  - Oakes, Guy, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Odaka, Kunio, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - Orenstein, Henry, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 46)
  - P - R -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 47)
  - The Pacific Sociological Association (The Pacific Sociological Review), 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
  - Pandey, Rajendra, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 48)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1964-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
  - Pelez, Shimon, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
  - Perin, Constance, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 49)
  - Philipps, Walter (Research Assistant to R.Bendix), 1960-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 50)
  - Poerschke, Frank, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Polydorides, Nicos D., 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Pope, Saxton, 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 51)
  - Pope, Whitney, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - Popkin, Jeremy, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - Prager, Jeffrey, 1979-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 52)
  - Raphael, E.O., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
  - Rich, Henry, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 53)
  - Rapoport, David, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 54)
  - Riesman, David, 1946-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 55)
  - Rokkan, Stein, 1961-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 56)
  - Rosberg, Carl G., 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Rosenstein, Eliezer, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 57)
  - Rosovsky, Henry, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Rossetti, Carlo, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 58)
  - Roth, Guenther, 1964-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 59)
  - Rothblatt, Sheldon, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Rozman, Gilbert, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Rudolph, Lloyd I., 1979; 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - Rustow, Dankwart A., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 60)
  - S -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 61)
  - Scheibert, Peter, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 62)
  - Schiff, Avraham, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 62)
  - Schluchter, Wolfgang, 1977-1991 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 63)
  - Schmädeke, Jürgen, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
  - Schmid, Carol, 1978-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
  - Schmitter, Philippe C., 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 64)
  - Schneider, Reinhart, 1971-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 65)
  - Schoefer, Christine, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
  - Schütz, Wilhelm Wolfgang, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 66)
  - Schwan, Alexander and Gesine, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Sciulli, David, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 67)
  - Seliger, Martin, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Selvin, Hanan C., 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 68)
  - Selznick, Philip, 1956; 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
  - Sennett, Richard, 1976-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 69)
  - Shils, Edward, 1973-1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 70)
  - Showalter, Ralph, 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Shuen, Yin, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Singer, Milton, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 71)
  - Skocpol, Theda, 1977-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 72)
  - Somjee, A. H., 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Spalek, John M., 1979-1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 73)
  - Sprondel, Walter, 1974-1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 74)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 74)
  - Stiewe, Werner, 1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Strong, Tracy B., 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Stunkard, Albert J., 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 75)
  - Suzuki, Yoshitaka, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
  - Sweet, Louise, 1974-1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 76)
  - T - Z -- recommendations and miscellaneous correspondence - [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 77)
  - Tar, Zoltan, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
  - Tibi, Bassam, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
  - Tiryakian, Edward A., 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
  - Todd, John, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
  - Toru, Haga, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
  - Trentini, Giancarlo, 1983; reprint (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 80)
  - Umpatscheh, Andreas, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 80)
  - von Thadden, Rudolf, 1976-1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 81)
  - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 82)
  - Walder, Andrew, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 83)
  - Wasserstein, Abraham, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 83)
  - Weil, Frederick, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 83)
  - Weidemann, Conrad, 1989-1991 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 84)
  - Weintraub, Jeff, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 85)
  - Westie, Frank R., 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 85)
  - White, Harrison C., 1976-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 85)
  - Wilson, Everett, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 86)
  - Wirth, Louis, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 86)
  - Wittebur, Klemens, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 86)
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
  - Wolfson, Manfred, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
  - Womack, Brantley, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
  - Woodhouse, Charles, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 88)
  - Wright, George, 1981-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 89)
  - Yellin, Joel, 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 90)
  - Young, Nigel, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 90)
  - Zammito, John, 1977-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 91)
  - Employment, 2.250 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 92-100)
    - Employment offers, 1949-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 92)
    - Australia National University / University of Canterbury, New Zealand, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 93)
    - Chinese University of Hong Kong, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 94)
    - Harvard University, Center for European Studies Colloquium, 1983 November 18-1983 November 20 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 95)
    - Northwestern University, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 96)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1948-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 97)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1970-1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 98)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Department of Sociology, 1947-1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 99)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Science Colloquium, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 100)
  - Employment, 2.251 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1-4)
    - University of Colorado, Boulder, 1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
    - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
    - University of Minnesota, 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
    - University of Pittsburgh (Leonard Plotnicov), 1965-1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
    - University of Texas at Austin, 1977-1978 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
    - Yale University (Wendell Bell), 1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 2.252 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5-20)
    - The American Journal of Sociology, 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
    - Anchor Books, 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - The Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - C.H. Beck'sche Verlagsbuchhandlung (Günther Schiwy), 1976-1977 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1978 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
    - Columbia University Press (John D. Moore), 1977-1978 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Euramerica, S.A., 1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
    - Hermann Luchterhand Verlag, 1968-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1962-1965 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
    - John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
    - Little, Brown and Company (re:State and Society), 1967 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
    - The Nation, 1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
    - The New Leader, 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
    - Oxford University Press, 1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
    - Social Research (Arien Mack), 1979 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
    - Sociological Inquiry (Harry M. Johnson), 1979 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
    - Staatslexikon der Görres-Gesellschaft, 1982-1983 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
    - Tavistock Publications Limited, 1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
    - Universitätsverlag Konstanz, 1977-1978 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
    - University of California Press (State and Society), 1973-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
    - University of California Press (Max Weber; Nation Building and Citizenship; Economy and Society), 1973-1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
    - University of California Press (Kings or People), 1977-1980 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
    - University of California Press (Force, Fate and Freedom), 1982-1985 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1986 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
    - Yale University Press, 1983 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
    - Zeitschrift für Soziologie (Wolfgang Lipp), 1978 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
- Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Bendix, 1930-1991; 3; 275 file folders
  This series contains both published and unpublished writings by Bendix. Included in this series are early writings in German (1930-1938), background materials and early versions of several book publications, including Social Mobility in Industry (1959), Embattled Reason (1970), and extensive files pertaining to Work and Authority in Industry (1956). The series also contains numerous essay and lecture texts, including many on various aspects of the writings of Max Weber, and reviews of the works of others.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Early writings in German, 1930-1938; 3.1
    - Poetry, 1930s (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
    - Untitled sketches, 1930s (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
    - "Thesen zu Karl Mannheims: 'Ideologie und Utopie'", 1932 May 22; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
    - "Über die Religiosität im Atheismus", 1932 June 18; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
    - "Mensch und Religion", 1932 August 2; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)
    - "Aphorisma", 1933 March 26; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 6)
    - "De Caesare et Christo", 1933 March 31; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 7)
    - "Zur Strukturanalyse des menschlichen Geistes", 1933 April 16-1933 May 25; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 8)
    - "Für die, die verweilen", 1933 May; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 9)
    - "Philosophie und Leben", 1933 June 29-1933 December 13; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 10)
    - "Das Problem des Irrationalen und der inneren Transcendenz", 1934 February-1934 March 23; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 11)
    - "Versuch einer Funktionsanalyse der menschlichen Struktur", 1934 November 15-1935 May 12; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 12)
    - Untitled, ca. 1935; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 13)
    - "Der Begriff der Wahrheit im wissenschaftlichen Denken", 1935 June 16; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 14)
    - "Die Aufgabe geschichtlicher Besinnung", ca. 1936-1937; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 15)
    - "Die Bedeutung der menschlichen Existenz im Zusammenhang der geistesgeschichtlichen Entwicklung", 1937 April 7; typescript (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 16)
    - Untitled typescript on Kant, 1938 April 22 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 17)
  - Full-length works, 1947-1956; 3.2; typescripts cubic ft.
    - The Public Servant in a Democracy: A Study of the Social Origins and Careers of Higher Federal Administrators. Ph.D. dissertation, University of Chicago, 1947 June (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 18)
    - The Public Servant in a Democracy. Handwritten critical comments by Ludwig Bendix, Undated (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 19)
    - Higher Civil Servants in American Society, 1949 (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 20)
      Notes, interviews.
    - Class, Status and Power (1953, with S. M. Lipset). Early outlines, Undated (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 21)
    - Work and Authority in Industry (1956). Initial drafts: "Managerial Ideologies", Undated; typescripts (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 22)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Class Relations and Industrialization", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 23)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Class Relations and Industrialization in Europe -- An Essay", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 24)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early version: "Class Relations in Societies Undergoing Industrialization", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 25)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Ideologies, Class-Relations and Industrialization", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 26)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "The Ideology of Anti-Industrialism", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 27)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "The Ideology of Anti-Industrialism", Undated (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 28)
      Critical comments by Ludwig Bendix, handwritten and mimeo.
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Industrialization and Intellectual Life", Undated; mimeograph (Box 4 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 29)
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Industrialization and Intellectual Life", Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 1)
      Materials, notes.
    - Work and Authority in Industry. Early versions: "Social Classes and the Political Community", Undated; typescript, mimeograph (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 2)
    - Work and Authority in Industry, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 3)
      Notes on Russian labor relations.
    - Work and Authority in Industry, Undated (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 4)
      Notes on Soviet and East German managerial strategies.
    - Social Mobility in Industrial Society (1959, with S. M. Lipset). Early version: "Power and the Elites in American Society", Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (3-Published and Unpublished Writings of Reinhard Ben), Folder 5)